Atta Ullah

Office: Room # 97, Hostel 4 Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad, 45320 Islamabad (Pakistan) @ attaullah@cs.qau.edu.pk; Homepage Google Scholar GitHub

About

I am a final-year master's student expected to graduate in December 2023 from Quaidi-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. My research area focuses on graph machine learning (GML), an emerging field with far-reaching applications in diverse industries, from drug discovery and optimization to recommendation and forecasting. I work on conspiracy source detection by considering the propagation pattern of information that spreads in the social network. I use a graph neural network to embed the propagation pattern and classification the source as accurate or conspiracy.

Education

M.Phil. Computer Science

Sep. 2021-Present

- Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan
- Dissertation: Identifying Misinformation Spreaders on Twitter using Ego-Centric Network Embeddings
- Major Area of Study: Social Network Analysis, Graph Machine Learning
- Minor Area of Study: Artificial Intelligence

BS Computer Science

Aug. 2021

- University Of Swat
- Dissertation: Learning Management System

HSSC Aug. 2017

• Government PG Jahanzeb College Saidu Sharif

Research Experience

Master Student: Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad Sep. 2022 - July. 2023 Research areas: Conspiracy source detection in social networks, Graph Neural Network

Industry Experience

Full Stack Developer

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2021

Max tech Developers

As a Full Stack Developer, my primary role was developing both the front and back
end. The back-end responsibilities included database design and implementation
and developing an API for extracting data. On the front end, I was responsible for
developing web applications using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and React.
Additionally, I worked on Android app development using Java and XML. I used
PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, Node.js, and Express.js in the development process.

Software Developed

• Learning Management System.

Firstly, the application functions as a student record database where administrative authorities can input the daily records of each student. This includes completed classwork, homework assignments, test and exam results, in-school moral/behavioral activities, and physical assessment reports. Additionally, school management authorities can share vital notifications regarding upcoming school events. Secondly,

our proposed application allows parents to easily monitor their children's school activities and complete records daily with a single touch, providing them the convenience of checking at their preferred time.

- Thalassemia Centers Management System. (Link to the source code)
- IT Academy Center Institute Management System (Link to the source code)
- Car-Park-Finder (Link to the source code)
- Blood-Donor-Finder (Link to the source code)
- Quiz App (Link to the source code)
- Medicine Order App (Link to the source code)
- Commonwealth toner and ink (Link to the app)
- ZAMA SHOPS Buy & Sell Pakistan (Link to the app)

Teaching Experience

Quaid-i-Azam University

Teaching Assistant for:

Feb. 2023 - July 2023

- Data structure and Analysis of Algorithms (Spring 2023)
- Problem Solving and Programming (Spring 2023)

Max tech Computer Institute

Teaching Assistant for:

Dec. 2019 - Dec 2020

- C++ Programming (2020)
- Android App development (2020)

Awards and Honors

• Capital University of Science & Technology (CUST) , Winner of Hackathon Competition (8th Episode of ExcITeCup 2023), Highest Prize Money Award

Certification (courses)

- Java for Android (Coursera)
- Using Python to Interact with the Operating System (Coursera)
- Linear Algebra for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)
- Introduction to Docker (Coursera)
- Health Data Science Foundation (Coursera)
- Linear Algebra for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)
- Web Application Technologies and Django (Coursera)
- Crash Course on Python (Coursera)
- Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra (Coursera)
- AI for Medical Diagnosis (Coursera)
- Calculus for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)

Programming Tools

• Python, Networkx, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, PyG, PyTorch, Deep Graph Library, SQL, C++, PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, NodeJs, React, JavaScript, Java, Django